JOSEPH DAYSSOL

dayssoljoseph@gmail.com • (+33) 6 22 33 18 30 • Xing/profile

Kottwitzstraße 19 • 20253 Hamburg, Germany

Date of birth: 13 October 1982 • Nationality: French



SENIOR FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Result-driven and adaptable professional with 15+ years of comprehensive experience in software and web development using object-oriented languages for IT companies, insurances and banks. Problem solving and analytical thinking skills, a fast learning-curve and ability to adopt to evolving IT trends. A dedicated professional with the drive and skill-set to excel in a senior software engineer role enhancing the company's ability to provide clients with modern and value-added software.

EDUCATION				
2008 – 2010	IAE Paris – Sorbonne Business School, France Master of Business Administration (MBA)			
2000 – 2005	University of Corté - Science Faculty, France Master in Information Technology (5 years degree in Programming)			
CORE COMPETENCIES				
Programming:	Java, JavaScript, Angular, Vue.js, C#, PL-SQL, HTML5, CSS			
Methods/Framework:	V-Cycle, SCRUM, Hibernate, Maven			
Tools:	SVN, Git, Jenkins, Jira, Confluence, Oracle			
Other skills:	Project Management, Business Strategy, IT-Marketing, Production Management			
PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE				
Jan 2020- June 2020	NautilusLog Gmbh , Hamburg, Germany			
	Senior Software Engineer – Internal work			
Jan 2019 – Dec 2019	Wibas Etarate, Hamburg, Germany			
	Senior Software Engineer – Mission for ExpressSteuer			

	Senior Software Engineer – Internal work
Jan 2019 – Dec 2019	Wibas Etarate, Hamburg, Germany
	Senior Software Engineer – Mission for ExpressSteuer
Jan 2014 – Jan 2019	Effisoft, Paris, France
	Senior Software Engineer – Internal work
Apr 2012 – Oct 2013	April, Paris, France
	Senior Software Engineer – Internal work
Jun 2011 – Feb 2012	SunGard, Paris, France
	Senior Software Engineer – Mission for BNP Paribas
Jan 2011 – Jun 2011	Capgemini, Paris, France
	PO – Integration Testing Engineer – Mission for Banque Populaire
Aug 2007 – Jan 2011	MACSF, Paris, France
	Software Engineer – Internal work
Oct 2005 – Jul 2007	Aubay, Paris, France
	Software Engineer – Missions for Veolia, Orange

LANGUAGES

T 1.	NT . 4
French	Native

English Advanced (C1)

NAUTILUSLOG - Web engineer (Hamburg, permanent contract from Jan 2020 to Jun 2020)

Senior web engineer of a innovative web application

Development of a ship logbook web app, using last technologies and current standard of development.

Frontend website with Angular, Backend with Java / Spring.

Use of SCRUM and Agile development in coordination with a international team.

Code management with GIT (Pull request and code review). Integration tests with Postman /Selenium.

Languages: Angular, Java, Springboot

Technical environment: IntelliJ, Visual Studio Code, GIT, Postman, Selenium, Jira, BitBucket

WIBAS - Lead software engineer (Hamburg, permanent contract from Jan 2019 to Dec 2019)

Senior full stack software engineer of a tax declaration web app

Development of a tax declaration web app, starting from scratch with free choice of architecture and technology. Frontend website with Angular, Backend and API with the tax office (Elster) with Java/Springboot. CI/CD chain using Gitlab and Heroku. Tests with Springboot and Postman.

Languages: Angular, Java, MongoDB

Technical environment: Visual Studio code, Ecclipse, Postman.

EFFISOFT (Paris, permanent contract from January 2014 – present)

Effisoft delivers software solutions to the insurance, re-insurance and risk management industries worldwide.

Senior full stack software engineer in the interface team of Webxl

Implementation of new features, fixture of defects and deployment of releases in internal environment using agile method and best practices.

Tasks and achievements:

- Development of business features, resulting in two complete releases per year by achieving a significantly high quality of a 98%+ defect rate.
- Application of Scrum methodology: conduction of meeting with product owners cost estimation sprint planning and reviews, resulting in an agile adaptation to the changing needs of international customers.
- Continuous development and continuous integration using Maven, Jenkins, resulting in a significant cost reduction and a sustainable quality improvement.
- Efficient fixture of production defects according to the contractual provisions of short-time customer requests, providing reliable on-time-delivery.

Languages: Java, Silverlight, Javascript, Vue.js, Maven, Hibernate

Technical environment: Eclipse, Visual Studio, SVN, PL-SQL Developer, WebStorm, Jenkins, Selenium

APRIL INTERNATIONAL (Paris, permanent contract from April 2012 – October 2013)

April International is an e-commerce insurance broker.

Senior full stack software engineer in the IT department

Development and implementation of new insurance products subscription for the e-commerce international website providing dynamic pricing and connecting with the insurance software.

Tasks and achievements:

- Application maintenance of existing subscription system and development of new subscription website, resulting in a 20% increase of sales revenues on the web channel.
- Sustainable reform of quote and certificate generation in multiple languages.

• Efficient fixture of production defects according to the contractual provisions of short-time customer requests, providing reliable on-time-delivery.

Languages: Java, Struts, EJB 3.0, Hibernate 4

Technical environment: Eclipse, SQL Developer, SOAP UI, Mantis, Redmine, SVN, Selenium

BNP CIB (Paris, mission for SunGard, from June 2011 – February 2012)

BNP Paribas Corporate and Institutional Banking (CIB) is the global investment banking branch of BNP Paribas.

Senior full stack software engineer in the structured finance department

Development of web-based software which serves to manage loans. The team consisted of three developers, one database architect and one project manager. The team applied CMMI and the quality standards of BNP CIB.

Tasks and achievements:

- Development of responsive pages and of high-volume withstanding back-end, applying design patterns, defensive and interface programming, increasing the competence of the team with respect to various technologies and resulting in the integration of quality standards at the development level.
- The reliable on-time-delivery within short deadlines allowed the customer to shift Excel files to a powerful and secure web application.

Languages: Java, Javascript, Java Server Page, Struts 2, Hibernate, Jquery, CSS, XHTML

Technical environment: Eclipse, TOAD, ANT, Junit, CVS

Banque Populaire (Paris, mission for Capgemini, from January 2011 – June 2011)

Groupe Banque Populaire is a French group of cooperative banks.

Product owner and integration testing engineer

Redesign of web site of Banque Populaire, applying SharePoint 2010 and C# specific development. The team in charge of the project applied SCRUM.

Tasks and achievements:

- Preparation and conduction of meetings with managing directors in Nantes elaborating on client's needs and defining potential strategies with regard to the envisaged redesign of the website of Banque Populaire
- Drafting of user story and technical documentation successfully implemented by the developers
- Acquisition of SCRUM methodology, which significantly improved the visibility of the respective status of the project.
- Continuous automated integration resulted in reduced defects.

Languages: C#, Sharepoint 2010

Technical environment: Visual Studio – Hudson

MACSF (Paris, permanent contract from August 2007 – January 2011)

MACSF is a health insurance company, their customers are mainly health professional workers.

Java engineer in the IT department

Development of internal software for accounting, loss and savings in the context of technology shift from Cobol to JSP interfaces. Development of the client's subscription web site using .NET.

Tasks and achievements:

- Development of new software interfaces which highly improved the user experience and performance.
- Development of generation tools, drafting of documentation and providing java training to Cobol developers, resulting in a sustainable integration of the technology change.
- Development of the life insurance web site and health care web site Libéa using .NET, resulting in an innovative and efficient channel of subscription on the web.

Languages: Java, Java Server Page, C#, Cobol

ORANGE (Paris, mission for Aubay, May 2007 – July 2007)

Orange is a French multi-national telecommunications corporation.

Java engineer in the research department

The subject of the research project was the integration of Orange web services in the CRM SalesForce.

Tasks and achievements:

- Development of responsive web pages, fully compliant with time and budget constraints.
 Successful Integration of business web services in SalesForce, opening new business opportunities with highly

Languages: Java, Javascript, JQuery Technical environment: Eclipse, SalesForce